Tejas Shinde

| Ph: +91 97692 58261 | Email: tejas.shinde48@gmail.com |

| Mumbai | LinkedIn | GitHub |

Professional Summary

Highly skilled Data Analyst and Power BI Developer with 1.5 years of experience in the field. Demonstrated business and technical acumen to create and implement strategies that automate and streamline processes, resulting in a 95% improvement in data quality and accuracy. As a Business Analyst, trained colleagues on automation tools, achieving an 80% reduction in manual data entry.

Technical Skills

Visualisation Tools	Languages	Cloud & Database	Statistical Analysis
 Advanced Excel Power BI Tableau Desktop Certifications Google Data Analytics Certificate Google	 Advance SQL Intermediate Python 	MySQLSSMS	 Descriptive Statistics Data Sampling Techniques Oct 2024
SQL Intermediate Certificate Hacker Rank			Oct 2024

Projects:

Airbnb Data Analysis | Tableau | Project Link

- This project highlighted key metrics, such as average price per bedroom, price variations by zip code, annual revenue, and the distinct count of bedroom listings.
- There are several data tasks performed as data cleaning, data transformation to get the insights which indicated the price of room in Q3 and Q4 has is 20% high as compared to Q1 and Q2.
- Analyzed key market indicators, including average price per bedroom and annual revenue; identified significant price variations by zip code while determining 1,200 distinct bedroom listings to inform pricing strategies

Electric Vehicles Pattern Analysis | Power BI

- I conducted an EV charging behaviour analysis using Power BI, focusing on metrics like energy
 consumption, battery capacity, charging costs, and distance covered for BMW, Chevrolet, Hyundai, Nissan,
 and Tesla.
- This analysis uncovered peak charging times and cost variations across cities, providing actionable insights for EV efficiency and cost optimization.
- Hyundai Kona has the covered more than 5.85k (kms) compared to other brands.

Work History

Data Analyst - Intern Nov 2023 to Jul 2024

Ai Variant – Mumbai

- Analyzed and visualized data using Power BI and Excel to identify trends, driving actionable business insights.
- Optimized SQL for faster data retrieval, improving report generation times by 20%.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure data integrity, developing standardized KPIs in Tableau.

• Utilized data visualization and data modeling techniques in Tableau to analyze and present Airbnb data, focusing on data cleaning and delivering insights for strategic business intelligence

Operations Manager, Nov 2023 to Aug 2024

Fluidscapes Consultant (OPC) Pvt. Ltd. – Mumbai

- Utilized data analysis to optimize inventory management and operational processes, ensuring cost effective business operations.
- Developed dashboards to monitor key business metrics and identify areas for improvement.
- Increased reporting efficiency by 30% and reduced and Leveraged data analytics to optimize inventory levels, reducing stock by 15% through data-driven insights and continuous monitoring of key metrics
- Business Analyst Consultant, Aug 2022 to Sept 2023 This is That Company Pvt. Ltd.
- Business Development Manager,
 Jan 2022 to Jul 2022 BodySculptor
- Sales and Operations Manager,
 Feb 2019 to Dec 2021 Sarva Yoga
- Salon Business Manager, Jul 2017 to Jan 2019
 Jean Claude Biguine
- Team Leader, Sept 2016 to Jul 2017 Saundaryaveda
- Guest Service Coordinator Mar 2016 to Sept 2016 ITC Grand Central Hotel
- Store Manager, May 2014 to Aug 2015 Sbarro – Niagara Falls, Canada

Education

Data Analysis Certification

Excelr, Mumbai | Sep 2023 – Feb 2024

Hospitality Studies

Niagara College, Canada | 2013 – 2015

Hotel Management

Kohinoor College, Mumbai | 2010 – 2013

Commerce

Kirti College, Mumbai | 2008 – 2010

High School

Saraswati School, Mumbai | 1998 – 2010

Languages

- English (Upper Intermediate)
- Hindi (Upper Intermediate)
- Marathi (Upper Intermediate)